READING AND SPEAKING TASK
THE MILLION-Pound BANK NOTE
ACT II, SCENE IV
At the end of the month, Henry was very rich and didn't fear jail.
Dressed in the finest clothes,
he drove by the brother's house in Portland Place,
and,
seeing they were back, went to get Portia at her friend's home.
My dear, the way you look today,
it would be a crime not to ask for a good salary for the job they'll give to me.
Oh, please remember that if we ask for too much,
we may get no salary at all, and then what'll happen to us
with no way in the world to earn a living?
Good morning, gentlemen. Portia,
these are the men who helped me.
So very nice to meet you, kind sirs.
Gentlemen, I'm ready to report.
Err, Portia, I...
We're both glad to hear it. For now we can decide the bet
which Roderick and I made.
If you've won for me, you shall have any job as my gift.
Have you got the million-pound bank note?
Here it is, sir.
I've won! Now what do you say, Roderick?
I say that I've lost twenty thousand pounds. I never would have believed it.
Why, that is amazing, man.
Come, let's be going now, Portia.
But wait, wait, the job, you know. I must give you a job,
as I promised.
Well, thank you very much, but I really don't want one now.
Henry, I'm disappointed in you.
You didn't thank the gentleman properly.
May I do it
for you?
Let me see you try.
Portia walks over to Roderick and gives him a hug.
Then she sits in Oliver's lap,
puts her arms around his neck and kisses him on the cheek.
Oliver begins laughing.
Papa, he says he doesn't want anything else from you.
My dear, is that your papa?
He's my stepfather and the dearest one that ever was.
Oh, my dearest, dear sir, I regret what I said. You have got a job open
that I want.
Name it.
Son-in-law.
Well, well, well. But you've never had such a job before.
How can I be sure you can do it successfully?
Try me. Oh, do, I beg of you. Give me thirty or forty years and-
Oh, well, all right.
Are Portia and Henry happy?
There are not enough words in the biggest dictionary to describe it.
Did the people of London have a good time with this bit of news?
Yes. Portia's stepfather took that banknote back to the Bank of England
and cashed it.
The banknote was then useless for money,
but was his wedding gift to the young couple.
Yes, the banknote was worth millions of dollars,
but not worth one-tenth as much as how Henry felt about Portia.